Never forget why you are the church.
I want you to turn your Bible to Revelation 8 tonight.
Revelation 8.
We're continuing in the overview of the 7 trumpets.
If you don't have the notes, Mark is coming around to give them to you.
Um, As I was
looking over this, um, and there's just so much.
I'm gonna, my goal is to start moving
a little bit quicker, but man, once I see something, I don't
know if it's just like me being a spiritual nerd.
Uh, I just can't, I can't move past it.
And so we just, this is where we're at.
But for Tom's sake, we're not going to review the 1st four.
Um, if you have missed those, because we're looking at the
trumpets of judgment, uh, they are on our website, they're on our app,
they're on our media player, so you can go and see those anytime
you want and and stream those and view those.
Uh, you can listen to them, you can watch them, uh, all the things.
So that's a pretty awesome thing that we have here at Cedar Grove.
But 2 weeks ago, we saw the Erie announcement of
the last 3 trumpets.
This is commonly known as the 3 woes.
Revelation 813, says, then I looked and I heard an eagle flying
in mid heaven, saying with a loud voice, whoa,
whoa, whoa, to those who dwell on the earth, because
of the remaining blast of the trumpet of the 3 angels who
are about to sound.
Something different was coming.
Remember, there's kind of a progression happening to
where each and every stage of this, it gets worse and worse and worse.
And so if you thought things were bad thus
far, these last 3 trumpets are going to just get worse.
So we're going to pray, get into it and get going.
Father again, I thank you, Lord.
And got to ask you just to give us wisdom and discernment.
God, I pray this study.
For those, if there's anyone here who's lost tonight.
God, I pray that this study inflicts terror upon
their spirit, God, draw them unto Jesus.
Jesus is the only way to not have to experience any of this.
So, Lord God, I pray if there are those who are saved, then are born again.
God, I pray that we do not fear what is to come, but we put our faith in you.
God, we thank you, we love you, since Jesus name pray.
Everybody said that?
Amen.
So we looked at last time, Trumpet 5.
In Revelation 9, verse one through 11, when I can
read it for time's sake, we learn of an army of locusts.
We can tell this is different than the 1st four.
We are now dealing with the demonic realm.
There's a star that falls from heaven, most
likely a fallen angel that has given the keys to the
bottomless pit.
He opens the abyss and out comes an army of locusts with
the power of scorpions.
And here's the most, if you ask me, the most horrific
detail of all this is this.
They are directed to not go after the trees or
the grass or anything.
They are told specifically to go after those
who are not sealed on the earth.
And they're also they don't have the permission to kill.
This is only torture.
For 5 months.
This army, this demonic army is going to torture those upon
the earth.
They cannot take life.
They can only torture.
We do not know what these locals will actually be.
There's a lot of speculation.
Is this, is this army is this helicopters, what, like, what is this?
We can only speculate, but we know that this is the
only way John, you had to describe them with the knowledge that he had of the time.
We know also this army has a king in Revelation 9, verse 11.
And they had a king over them, which is the angel, the bottomless pit
whose name in the Hebrew tongue is Abaddon, but in
the Greek tongue hath his name Apollyon.
Now, this is a targeted and methodical torture campaign.
Now remember, the atmosphere, and environment,
and landscape of the earth has radically been hindered through the previous judgments.
It's already not comfortable to be here.
Does that make sense?
I mean, I mean, the water is all
bitter, the oceans is all blood or at least a 3rd of
each, you know, the trees are a 3rd gone.
All the grass is burn up.
Things are already not good, and now you have a demonic
army solely here to torture.
Guys, aren't you glad for Jesus?
There's nowhere to hide, there's nowhere to go.
and it's not over.
Revelation 9, verse 12.
The 1st one was passed.
Behold, 2 woes are still coming after these things.
And that brings us to Trumpet 6.
We see in Revelation 9, verse 13 to 21.
We're going to read quite a bit here.
Remember, as we, these last 3 woes, these last 3
Trump, there's a lot more description of each, starting in
verse 13 than the 6th angel sounded, and I heard a
voice from the 4 horns of the golden altar, which is before God.
One saying to the 6th angel who had the trumpet, released
the 4 angels who are bound at the great river Euphrates.
And the 4 angels who had been prepared for the hour and
day and month and year were released so
that they would kill a 3rd of mankind.
The number of the armies of the horsemen were 200 million, and I heard the number of them.
And this is how I saw in a vision, the horses, and those
who sat on them, the riders had breastplates, the color of fire,
and hyacinth, and a brimstone, and the heads of the horses
are like the heads of lions, and out of their mouths proceed
fire and smoke and brimstone.
A 3rd of mankind was killed by these 3 plagues by
the fire and the smoke, and the brimstone which proceedeth out of their
mouths, for the power of the horses in their mouth and in
their tails, for the tails like serpents, and they have heads, and
with them, they do harm.
Verse 20, the rest of mankind who were not killed by these plagues.
Did not repent of the works of their hands.
So as to not so as not to worship
demons, and the idols of gold and silver, and of brass and of stone,
and of wood, which can neither see, nor hear, nor walk.
And they did not repent of their murders, nor their sorceries,
nor their immorality, nor of their thefts.
And that's a lot for one trumpet right there.
So we're going to try to go through this, so we kind of understand what's going on here.
In the tabernacle from Exodus.
Now, I want you to understand something.
The Bible is interconnected from the beginning to the end.
Okay, that's one of the beautiful characteristics
of God's word, is that everything that we read,
starting from Genesis, that it goes all the way to Revelation.
As a matter of fact, that's why the Bible, we
have proof the Bible is the word of God.
Not only is it the most evidence manuscript
ever, ancient manuscript ever, but it is also literally you
have over 40 authors, over 7 countries,
3 continents, over 1,600 years and several cultures.
And the entire Bible is one storyline beginning to finish.
Right?
I was teaching the kids this morning.
The Bible has one theme, and that's redemption.
The Bible has one hero and that's Jesus.
The Bible has one villain, and that's the devil, and the
Bible has one purpose, and that's the glory of God.
Listen, that is a miracle in of itself.
Amen?
If I asked all of you right here to give me a story of how tonight went.
The same event that we just all sat through.
I get a different story, different perspective, different
outcome, different this, different that.
Someone would have a bad experience there, here or there.
It would not be cohesive.
The Bible is times a 1000000 of that, and
it's a cohesive, unified story of Jesus.
That's pretty cool, eh, man?
I don't know about you.
But anyway, so we go back to Exodus.
Right?
In the tabernacle from Exodus, there was a golden altar that had
4 horns, one on each corner.
These horns were overlaid with pure gold.
Now, if you want to find this, you can go to Exodus 30 and do your own study on this.
But the high priest would perform annual atonement
by applying blood to these horns.
Now, according to a mentor expository
commentary, I'm going to read this to you.
This ritual background illuminates Revelation symbolism.
The horns represented a covering of sins through
blood, ensuring that God's power emanating from
the altar, blessed rather than devastate believers.
Revelation 9 draws this picture from Leviticus
4, where sins are covered in Christ's blood so that God's
decree won't harm the faithful.
So, in other words, what that was, the blood upon the
horns of the altar in the tabernacle.
Okay?
That's what we're at right now.
That symbolizes atonement, a covering of our sin.
Now, we know that was just looking forward to
Christ at Calvary.
Amen?
Now that he's shed his blood for the remission of our sins.
We are covered by the blood of Jesus.
We have been atoned for.
We are forgiven and delivered.
Praise God.
Amen.
So in the Old Testament, horns represented atonement,
that is a covering.
Now, In Revelation, horns
symbolize power, judgment.
Therefore, if we look at the position and number of these horns
in Revelation 9, knowing about what we know about their
placement in a tabernacle in Exodus 30, this means
that we can actually clearly see what's going on here.
These are 4 horns, or they're 4 horns, right?
The biblical numerology and symbolism for
the number 4 represents the earth and creation.
God finished the material universe, including
the sun, moon, and stars on the 4th day.
Adrian Rogers and one of his sermons, put it like this.
beyond atonement imagery.
Horns symbolize power throughout Revelation,
a meaning reinforced by their number and placement.
In biblical prophecy, horns represent power
and fore represents the earth number.
So the four horns signify universal power extended across the world.
The altar itself functions as a place of both judgment
and redemption.
Speaking of God's power and salvation, and judgment.
Two things can be true here.
These horns represent the protective covering of Christ atoning
work for believers, while also expressing God's complete power
to execute worldwide judgment.
I want to say this real quick though.
Here's the devastating truth.
The same blood that is applied to my account.
Okay, the word is imputed, right?
That is put upon my account.
The same blood that washes me clean of my sin.
is the same blood that will hold someone guilty of their sin.
Are you with me?
In other words, when I receive Jesus,
I'm covered.
But if I reject Jesus.
I'm very much so uncovered.
And so I'm guilty of my sin.
That is what should cause urgency in our life.
We know that the same blood of Jesus can both cause guilty
and innocent for those that either reject or receive.
Y'all women are not saying amen.
Amen.
So there's a voice in these 4 horns and a voice tells the angel with
a trumpet to release these 4 angels who are bound at the Euphrates River.
These 4 bound angels are obviously demons.
Nowhere in scripture will we ever find a holy
angel bound ever, right?
So I believe, and according to scripture and scholars
believe that these are demons, fallen angels.
Now, there are some interesting details here with the releasing of these 4 demons.
First, they were released at the precise right time they have been prepared for.
Look at Revelation 9, verse 15.
And the 4 angels who have been prepared for the hour and
the day and month and year were released.
Think about that for a second.
I want you to know something.
God has a plan, and it is precise.
Nothing that has happened, has surprised him.
Nothing that has happened is outside of his time.
As a matter of fact, God himself is outside of time.
Amen?
He doesn't operate as we operate.
And so he has prepared.
He has prepared these fallen angels.
These demons are prepared for the
exact time to be released.
Only God knows that.
Isn't it funny how the scripture says in the gospels that
no one knows the day nor the hour?
You see what I'm saying?
So in other words, we can speculate all we want.
All we have to trust is that God knows exactly what he's going to
do exactly what he's going to do.
So we may not understand everything, but we must know that God
has everything planned out perfectly to accomplish his will.
Second, not only is it perfectly precisely
timed, but second, once these demons were released,
an army of 200 million mounted troops were released as well.
I don't know about you.
That's a big old army right there.
Now, who are these troops?
Some believe this is an army of demons.
And if you read a description, they don't sound like humans, right?
If you read what we read, again, for time state, you can read it later.
But it doesn't sound very human to me.
The weapons we see them use, fire, sulfur, and
smoke are common supernatural weapons associated with hell.
So we see that the 1st view is that they are a demonic army.
The other view is there simply an army of immeasurable
amount and might.
In other words, they might be humans, they might not.
Uh, 200 million would have been an unfathomable
number in John's time.
As a matter of fact, it's really unfathomable, even today, to have a 200
million person army.
So also, he heard the number rather than seeing the number.
If 200000000 people were standing in front of me.
I couldn't even see the end of the army.
You see what I'm saying?
So he heard the number and not see it.
Interestingly enough, to put this in perspective, the largest
numbered army in the Old Testament was 200,000.
So it could have been that the number was given just to symbolize how massive
and destructive this armor was going to be.
Now, if you, if maybe you've lived long
enough and stuff, back in the 60s, I believe it was, or
maybe in Red China, I don't know exactly the time.
But if you remember, China came out
and said, hey, we have an army of 200000000 people.
Now here's here's the interesting part about that.
Where you think they got that number?
I don't know if it's here.
That's a pretty specific number, though.
Now, we know today that that's not true, right?
China's active army is a little over 2 million, and again, the
description of this army gives us no indication that it's a Chinese military force.
You got those people that love to attach names and people and groups
and stuff, the things in revelation.
I'm going tell you.
I don't think that's very wise thing to do.
It's fun to speculate, but it's not fun to make it firm.
Keep an opinion.
Does that make sense?
Keep it speculation because we don't know.
But whoever this army is and whatever they are, they
were no doubt destructive and deadly.
The Army of Locust from the 5th Trumpet was only permitted to torture.
This army has full permission to kill.
And kill is what they do.
Look at Revelation 915 again.
And so that they would kill a 3rd of mankind.
A 3rd of mankind.
Now let's do some Matthew.
connect everything together.
Remember, we're reading this on a weekly basis, right?
We're kind of going slow.
This is all happening pretty quickly and it's happening every day constantly.
The judgment does not end once it starts until it ends, right?
And so we see here that, um,
In the 4th seal, we know the 4th
the population has been killed already.
You add this with the 3rd remaining, right?
Or the 3rd that gets killed here, not counting any other casualties from the other judgments.
You get the math of half of the Earth's population from
the beginning of the Great Tribulations now has been killed.
Now.
That, that's a pretty big number.
I mean, that's one and 2 people on the earth are dead.
Revelation 918, a 3rd of mankind was killed by these 3 plagues,
by the fire, and the smoke and the brimstone, which proceeded out of their mouths.
How bad are these plagues?
There is one person who explained it like this.
The victims face incineration by
fire, asphyxiation by smoke and brimstone
and poisoning by sulfur.
One of the most horrific modes of death that you could probably imagine.
By the way, let's take a moment here.
Do these plagues ring any bells?
These demonic weaponry ring any bells.
What is what is a a form of judgment in
the Old Testament given on 2 cities and what was used there?
Think about it.
These 3 things echo the way God destroyed Sodom and Gomorrah.
Teaching us that those who go down the same path will reach the same end.
Again, the Bible is connected all the way through church.
There's nothing that has happened.
that does not matter.
There's nothing in scripture, that does not matter.
Status portion of this, uh, text and revelation that was
found in response to those who actually lived through this.
Now, there's gonna be some that live through it, right?
If one out of 2 people die, that means that one out of 2 people live.
Does that make sense?
I don't know if I'm not a math major, but that's kind of that makes sense to me, right?
So there are people on the earth.
But let's read about what they do after this.
Look at this in verse 20.
The rest of mankind.
who were not killed by these plagues, did not repent
of the works of their hands.
so as not to worship demons and the idols of gold and silver
and a brass and of stone and wood, which can neither see nor hear nor walk.
And they did not repent of their murders, nor their sorceries, nor
their of their immorality, nor of their thefts.
If this does not show you the state of mankind that gets left behind.
I don't know what does.
You talking about the great delusion that God puts upon the earth this time.
See, there's people that think, well, you know what?
If I get left, I'll sow my wild oats and if
the rapture happens, I'll get left behind, then I'll give my life to Christ.
Not according to this.
According to this, you're going to be involved in sorceries, that's witchcraft.
That's magiccraft.
You're gonna be involved in sexual immorality.
You're going to be involved in theft.
You're gonna be involved in demon worship.
Guys, listen at this point.
It's full on delusion.
They're seeing all these things happen, people dropping left
and right, this demonic army of 200 million, whatever that means
in the text is killing everybody.
And yet they don't repent of their sin.
I can't think of anything more tragic than that.
All the death and terror, they refuse to repent.
Church, the world is preparing for judgment.
Think about all the sickness and death and sorrow that our sin creates in our life.
There are people right now walking and saying they're miserable.
They're sick, they're diseased.
They've lost everything.
They're on the verge of losing everything, and they know whatever it is, yet they won't repent.
People say all the time, well, you know, if I if
I knew better than I would.
Let me just tell you something, there is more accessibility to the gospel today than
there ever has been in the entire history of the world.
Now there's more, I believe there's more false profits today.
I believe it's more false teachers, and I believe that the enemy has done that on purpose, obviously.
But listen, there is there is churches on every corner.
Now, not every church cares about lost souls, but every
church that I think is worth their weight and salt does.
Amen.
So now we see people that refuse to repent of their sin.
We look at this and we read this and how could anybody see
all the things that were going on and not turn
from these wicked ways.
Not cry out, Jesus.
Okay, you got me.
Save me, Lord.
I believe you now.
Well, well, if we see them not doing that now.
They're seeing the judgment of God.
We're seeing the goodness of God today.
The grace of God today.
Listen, the Bible says it's the goodness of God.
It turns those to repentance.
So if we see all that God has done for us, yet we refuse
to repent of our sin, to turn away from what
once held us captive, well, we're no better than these people.
You understand what I'm saying tonight?
It'll be no different in the end.
I praise God.
that I'm on the atoning side of the horns at the altar.
I do not have to fear because I have been covered by
the blood of Jesus Christ.
The question tonight is very simple, have you?
Have you?
Now, listen, that's not a that's not a confusing question.
That's a that's if you had, that's a celebration question.
That's a, praise God, yes, I have.
But if you haven't, listen.
I know, I live.
I grew up under a preacher, man, he could he could preach hell very well.
You know what I'm saying?
I mean he's scared to death.
And listen, hell is scary.
Eternal torment is scary.
Possibly being on earth with this demonic
army is scary.
Eternal separation from God.
Is scary.
So listen, when I preach on hell or when another preacher preaches
on hell, if you leave there feeling warm and cuddly, he didn't preach on hell.
See, the world wants to, to, to,
uh, dumb down and numb us to what torment and judgment is going to be.
The world wants to tell you it doesn't matter what you do.
In the end, it's all going to work out.
Just do enough good to your bad and the scales
will be weighed in your favorite.
Let me just tell you something.
They will not.
There is none righteous, no, not one.
Aside from Christ.
Those that don't know him are going to hell, and we
want to do everything we can to stop that.
Why?
Because we know the answer.
His name is Jesus.
Amen?
So if you've been, if you're on the atoning side, hey, praise the Lord.
If you're not, listen, tonight's a good night to get on that side.
You say, what do I do?
All you got to do is confess with your mouth.
Jesus is Lord.
Why wait?
As a matter of fact, whether you say the lost, the Bible says you're going to do it anyway.
Amen?
It's kind of like when you make your wife mad, you know you're going to have to apologize at some point.
Might as well do it now.
You understand what I'm saying?
Listen, why wait?
Every knee will bow.
Every tongue will confess that Jesus Christ is Lord.
I do that today.
Amen.
And I pray you do as well.
So if you confess with your mouth that Jesus is Lord, believe in your heart
that God raised in front of dead, you will be saved.
When hezban eyes closed over this place.